IN SURGERY, SONG HA-YOUNG
（手术中 宋霞永）
Luckily, he's out of the woods for now.
幸运的是 他现在已经脱离了危险
Once we wrap up, we'll move him to the ICU
我们一结束手术 就把他转移到重症监护室
and monitor his recovery.
观察他的恢复情况
Thank you.
谢谢
Thank you. Good work.
谢谢 辛苦了
I should've taken better care of him.
我应该好好照顾他的
It's all right.
没事的
I know he's going to wake up soon.
他一定很快就会醒过来
He will.
是啊
Was I six years old then?
好像是我六岁的时候？
I went to an amusement park with my mother on Children's Day.
儿童节那天我和妈妈去了游乐园
That was the first time I saw a dead body.
那是我第一次见到尸体
You were pretty young.
已经过去很长时间了啊
The body was in the water.
尸体漂浮在水中
When I saw her face,
我看着那张脸
she didn't scare me.
没觉得害怕
She just looked very lonely.
她看着很孤单
"She must have been terrified."
“她一定吓坏了”
"She must've been lonely and in pain."
“她一定很孤单很痛苦”
That's what crossed my mind.
我当时是这么想的
So I wanted to reach out to hold her hand.
所以我想伸手 握住她的手
But I couldn't do that back then.
但我那时不能这样做
Just like what you've been doing,
就像一直以来的你
you probably did something to help the woman back then.
你当时可能为她做了力所能及的事
The Southwest Case serial killer, Nam Ki-Tae,
西南部连环杀人案的嫌疑人南基泰
said he'd kill again if he were released,
声称如果获释还是会继续杀人
which shocked the public.
这令民众深感震惊
We should hang men like him in the middle of Gwanghwamun
我们应该把像他这样的人 吊在光华门的中央
and stone them to death.
拿石头砸死他们
Why do people want to keep him alive? I really don't get it.
为什么人们想让他活着？我真不明白
What he did was inhumane. He doesn't deserve human rights.
他犯下那么惨无人道的罪行 他不配谈什么人权
Sir, I'm sorry, but could you turn that off please?
抱歉 你能不能关掉广播？
It's giving me a headache.
我听着头痛
Right. Sure.
好的
This news isn't that pleasant to listen to.
这新闻确实不怎么愉快
TOJUNG-DONG, ANYANG, GYEONGGI PROVINCE
（京畿道安阳市土井洞）
What?
什么？
I'm in Tojung-dong right now.
我现在在土井洞
I need to check out a missing person case.
我需要查一个失踪人口的案子
I'll be there later.
我一会就回去
HERO KARAOKE BAR
（英雄练歌房）
-Excuse me. -We're not open yet.
-打扰了 -我们还没有营业
I see.
我知道
-I'm from the police. -Hello.
-我是警察 -你好
You're my lady lady
你是我的梦中情人
I can't live without you
没有你我活不下去
The only thing I need in my life is you
你是我人生中唯一的需要
Are you having fun?
你玩得开心吗？
I got bored of waiting.
我都等得无聊了
Brief me.
给我报告一下
I told you over the phone.
我在电话里和你说了
So she left after singing here.
她唱完歌 离开这里
-And then she can't be reached. -Right.
-然后她就联系不上了 -好的
She left alone without a customer?
她独自离开的 没和客人一起？
Right.
是的
-That's it? -Right.
-情况就是这样？ -对
A woman in her forties was having fun with her customer here.
一个四十多岁的女人和客人在这享乐
And she left before the customer,
她在客人之前离开
and she can't be reached ever since.
然后就此失联
Is that really it?
真的是这样吗？
Right.
是的
Come on.
真是的
Chief Park.
朴股长
I came all the way here.
我大老远过来
You should have gotten a lead.
你总得有个什么线索吧
I didn't ask you to come here.
我没让你来啊
-You came here on your own. -Damn you.
-你自己来的 -真是的
You want me to report this
你想让我把这
as criminal intelligence?
当作犯罪情报来报告吗？
You do it. I'm out.
你去吧 我走了
Another woman from a different karaoke bar went missing in February.
另一家练歌房的一个女人 在二月份失踪
What?
什么？
MISSING PERSON
（寻人启事）
Two cases?
两起案件？
Yes.
是的
In February, a female worker
今年二月水原的一家练歌房
at a karaoke bar in Suwon went missing.
也有女性员工失踪
-But that case hasn't been filed yet. -Why not?
-但这件事还没有报案 -为什么？
A lot of these workers often go AWOL and move to another karaoke bar.
因为经常有员工失联 跳槽到其他店工作的情况
I guess that's why.
我想应该是这个原因
But how did you come across this case? This wasn't filed.
不过你是怎么找到未报警案件的
When I was on this case,
我调查时
my friend who worked at a karaoke bar in Suwon said
有个在水原练歌房工作过的朋友说
a worker there went missing out of the blue like this.
那里也有一个员工突然失联了
What's your take on this?
你有什么看法？
What I think doesn't matter.
我怎么看不重要
I'm just a cop.
我只是个警察
I investigate when I get the order.
收到命令 我就进行调查
And I don't when there's none.
没有命令 我就不调查了
You're a detective. You have no hunches?
你是警察 你没有第六感吗？
Show me that you're at least trying to open this case.
让我看到你至少在努力调查这个案子
There was a time
我之前
when I had to pay a hefty price
因为努力
because of my hunches.
付出过昂贵的代价
So I'm careful with everything.
所以我对待所有事都很谨慎
-Okay. You can leave now. -Okay.
-好吧 你可以走了 -好的
SUPERINTENDENT HEO GIL-PYO
（刑事科长 许吉票）
Well, both of the missing women
两起案件中失踪女性的
were in the same line of work.
职业是一样的
I couldn't find any connections
除了职业 我找不到
other than their profession.
其他共同点
Then…
那样的话…
is it possible that there was no motive behind these cases?
有没有可能这两起案件 是无动机犯罪？
Is that your hunch?
是你的直觉吗？
Well, every detective has a hunch.
每个警察都有直觉嘛
Go.
去吧
This way.
这边
Hello.
你好
YEONGTONG-GU, SUWON, GYEONGGI PROVINCE
（京畿道水原市灵通区）
SHIN MI-JUNG'S HOUSE
（申美静家）
You guys still haven't found her?
你们还没找到她吗？
Maybe something really happened to her
如果你们都找不到
if even you guys can't find her.
或许她真的出事了
That's not necessarily true.
那倒未必
We're here to check a few things.
我们是来核实一些事情的
Why come here twice
如果事情不严重
if this wasn't serious?
为什么要来两次呢？
Did she pay rent monthly?
她是按月付的房租吗？
She paid me monthly.
月付
If you couldn't reach her since February,
如果二月起你就联系不到她了
she must be behind on rent for three months.
她得拖欠三个月的房租了吧
Yes. But I can just deduct her rent
是的 但我可以从她的
from the initial deposit she made.
初始押金中扣除她的租金
I just hope she's okay.
我真希望她平安无事
So no one came after our visit?
我们上次来过后 没有人来吗？
Hey.
喂
Gosh.
天啊
She's been my tenant
过去三年
for the past three years.
她一直是我的租客
And I haven't seen her
而且我从没看过她
bringing people here.
带人来这里
She even stayed here during the holidays.
她节假日都是在这里过的
HERO KARAOKE BAR
（英雄练歌房）
SHIN MI-JUNG, NO FAMILY, CASE NOT FILED
（申美静 无家属 未立案）
MISSING PERSON
（寻人启事）
SING SING KARAOKE HOSTESSES ALWAYS AVAILABLE
（唱唱练歌房 女侍应随叫随到）
Yes, come in.
请进
Please call Song Ha-young.
我想见宋霞永
Inspector Song?
宋警卫？
I read the article and heard stories.
我看了报道 也听了些传闻
He has a knack for identifying connections between cases.
听说他很擅长找案件之间的关联
Hey.
喂
You really don't think it's a missing person's case?
你真不觉得这只是个人口失踪案吗？
Well, we have no concrete proof yet,
我们现在还没有确切的证据
but my hunch says otherwise.
但我的直觉告诉我没这么简单
If that's your hunch, it's probably right.
如果是你的直觉 那应该是对的
Mr. Heo, to what do I owe the pleasure of this call?
刑事科长大人 什么风把你吹来了？
Hey, how have you been?
你最近还好吗？
It took you this long to think of me?
你现在才想到我吗？
I just faxed something over to you.
我给你发了传真
It's a missing person's case. Can you look into it?
是一个失踪案 你能看一下吗？
Of course, you wouldn't call me for no reason.
当然 你果然是无事不登三宝殿
A missing karaoke bar employee? Is this the case?
练歌房服务员失踪？是这个案子吗？
No. We did receive a report for that one.
不是 那个案子我们已经接到报警了
Apparently, there's an unreported case.
显然 还有一起没有报警的案子
"Apparently"?
“还有一起”？
The person has no family or friends, and no one can reach her.
无缘无故失踪 似乎还断联了
What about this case?
那这起案子呢？
Both missing women
两名失踪女性
worked at karaoke bars.
都在练歌房工作
When the Special Crime Squad was all lost, you guys said
机搜队找不到头绪的时候 你们说过
cases with more than two common things may be connected.
有两个以上的共同点就要合理怀疑
These could be like the motiveless crimes you mentioned.
我怀疑这案子是你说的无动机犯罪
Can you go check with Inspector Song?
你能和宋警卫一起去看看吗？
Ha-young can't go.
霞永去不了
This is how you treat me now?
你现在对我这么生分吗？
You're hurting my feelings here.
你太让我伤心了
I'll go and check.
我会去查看的
Right, everyone says your team is in high demand now.
好吧 人人都说 你们组现在抢手得不行
I'll look into it and call you back.
我会了解情况 给你回电话的
Okay.
好的
Was that Superintendent Heo at Gyeonggi Police Agency?
刚刚是京畿警察厅的许科长吗？
Yes.
是的
I guess he hasn't heard about Inspector Song yet.
我猜他还没听说宋警卫的事吧
He's at Gyeonggi Agency now,
他在京畿厅
so he wouldn't know unless he looked into it.
除非他打听 不然不会知道的
This is a missing person's case.
听说这是个失踪案
Let's check the area, her movements, and the time of the incident.
我们查一下周边地区 她的行踪和事件发生的时间
Yes, sir.
好的
You're doing great.
你做得不错
Let's try that one more time.
我们再来一遍
Neuroparalysis?
神经麻痹吗？
When the fractures occurred at the time of the accident,
事故发生时造成了骨折
some of the nerves around the bones were damaged.
骨头周围的一些神经受到损坏
Thankfully, he can move his toes a little,
幸好 他的脚趾可以稍微动一下
and there isn't a complete loss of sensation,
感官并未完全丧失
so I'd say it's partial paralysis.
所以我说是不完全麻痹状态
In cases like this,
在这种情况下
he could recover through rehabilitative therapy.
他可以通过康复治疗恢复正常
The Seoul Metropolitan Police Agency
首尔地方警察厅
transferred gang members who had been
将通过非法赌场
embezzling cash through an illegal casino
侵吞现金的团伙成员
to the prosecution.
移交给检察机关
We wrapped up another case.
我们又结了一个案子
Good work, everyone.
各位辛苦了
How about a team dinner?
我们晚上聚个餐怎么样？
You want to drink, don't you? Sit down already.
你想喝酒了是吧？快坐下吧
The case isn't closed
案子还没有结
until the trial is over.
除非审判结束
I told them to contact us if they need more evidence.
我跟他们说 如果需要补充证据 可以联系我们
Okay.
好的
The gift certificates they received were used…
他们收到的礼券用于…
Right. Shouldn't we visit Inspector Song in the hospital?
好的 我们是不是应该 去医院探望一下宋警卫？
We haven't seen him since he moved to the general ward, right?
他转到普通病房后 我们还没探望他
That's right.
确实
GYEONGGI PROVINCIAL POLICE AGENCY
（京畿地方警察厅）
Look at you.
瞧瞧
Salute, Superintendent Heo Gil-pyo.
忠诚 许吉票刑事科长
Did you really come alone?
你真是一个人来的？
Why? Am I not good enough?
怎么？我一个人来不够吗？
I trained Korea's first criminal profiler.
我培养了韩国第一犯罪分析师
I'm in high demand.
我可是高级人才
Goodness. Don't be so difficult.
真是 别摆谱了
This is so cool.
这真酷啊
Oh, there he is.
他来了
This is Chief Park of the Serious Crime Unit.
这位是重案股的朴股长
You know him, right?
你认识他吧？
-Yes, we've met. -It's been a while.
-对 我们见过 -我们有一阵子没见了
Take a seat.
坐吧
Are you in charge of this case?
你负责这起案子吗？
No, Anyang Police Station is in charge,
不是 是安阳警察厅负责的
but it's a little strange.
但是有点不寻常
As for the unreported case in Suwon, she has no family.
水原未报警失踪的那位女性没有家人
That's right. That was probably why no one reported.
是这样的 或许是这个原因才没人报警
What's going on?
怎么回事？
Don't tell me…
别告诉我…
No, right?
不是吧？
Hey, I'm still new here.
喂 我才刚来没多久呢
Isn't that why you got in touch with me?
这不是你联系我的原因吗？
I'll go check the scene first.
我先去现场看看
I'll go with you.
我和你一起去
Slowly.
慢点
Inspector Song.
宋警卫
You came again.
你们又来了
Yes. Here, it's just something small.
是的 给 是我们的一点心意
My gosh, you always bring something.
哎呀 你们每次都带东西来
Where can I put this?
这个我可以放哪里？
You can put it over there.
你可以放在那里
I'll leave you to talk. Since you're here,
既然你们来了 就好好说说话吧
I should step out for lunch.
我也该出去吃午饭了
You didn't have to come all the way here.
你们不用费心过来的
I heard you were undergoing rehabilitation.
我听说你在做康复治疗
How are you feeling?
你感觉怎么样？
Not bad.
挺好的
Make yourselves at home.
别见外
I'll leave you to talk.
我出去 你们聊
Please stay. We'll leave soon.
请留步 我们不会待很久的
You'll feel more comfortable without me.
不管久不久 我不在 你们能更自在些
No, ma'am. That's not why we're here.
不是的阿姨 我们不是为公事来的
Yes, just stay.
是啊 留下吧
I want to step out for lunch.
我想出去吃饭
-All right, then. -Enjoy your lunch.
-那好吧 -祝您午餐愉快
Thank you.
谢谢
Oh, let me.
我来吧
I can do it by myself. Thank you.
我自己可以的 谢谢
You're doing much better now.
你现在好多了
Oh, we came to see you when you were in the ICU.
我们上次来看你 你还在重症监护室
That was when Captain Yoon and I met your mother.
我和尹组长也是那个时候见到阿姨的
Get better soon,
快点好起来
so we can work together again.
我们才能一起查案
Yes, you're in high demand at the moment.
是啊 现在可多人找你了
The Behavioral Analysis Team was already very busy,
犯罪行为分析组已经很忙了
but Chief Kook takes care of everything by himself now,
国股长一个人独揽大局
so he's always swamped these days.
所以这些天他一直忙得不可开交
But you're almost fully recovered now.
不过你现在差不多康复了
You should be able to return to work very soon.
应该很快就能回来工作了吧
I don't intend on going back.
我没有回去的意愿
As you can see, it's a quiet area.
如你所见 这里挺僻静的
Most customers of this karaoke bar are people who live in the area.
这家练歌房的客人大都住在附近
I don't see any security cameras.
我没看到有监控
That's right.
没错
The local precinct already questioned every customer who visited that day
地方分局询问了 当天光顾的每一位客人
but found nothing.
但是一无所获
But her phone…
但她的手机…
On the map, you'll see Daejong Lake.
在地图上 你可以看到大钟湖
TOJUNG-DONG
（土井洞）
DAEJONG LAKE
（大钟湖）
Daejong Lake? It's like a recreation area.
大钟湖？是个公园啊
It's estimated she went missing at around 1 a.m.,
据预测 她大约在凌晨一点失踪
so she didn't go there to hang out.
所以她不是去玩乐的
Nothing was caught on the security camera.
监控什么都没拍到
Any possibility of suicide?
有自杀的可能性吗？
The divers already searched the entire lake
潜水员把整片湖都找过了
but found nothing.
但没有发现
She didn't commit suicide.
她没有自杀
And the thing is,
而且
the person she last spoke to
她最后交谈的人
was her daughter.
是她的女儿
She told her she'd pick up fried chicken and head home.
她告诉女儿 回家的路上 她会顺路买炸鸡
You wouldn't be able to hail a taxi here.
这地方也不好打车
She probably took a bus at that stop.
她很可能在那个车站乘了公交车
Oh, right.
没错
We already looked into it and even interviewed the driver
我们查看过了 还调查了
who drove the last bus that night,
那天末班车的司机
and she wasn't on the bus.
她没坐那辆车
And the location where her phone last pinged
而她的手机最后显示的地点
is far from the bus route.
也不是公交车的路线
Then how did she get there?
那她是怎么到的那里？
She must've walked or…
她肯定是步行或者…
Perhaps abducted?
可能是被绑架去的？
-Hello. -I guess it's your day off.
-你好 -我猜你今天休息
-Yes. Your soybean paste stew was so good. -I see.
-是的 您上次给的酱汤真好吃 -是吗
-Really? I'll make it again. -Thank you. Goodbye.
-真的吗？那我再做给你吃 -谢谢 再见
Have a good day.
祝您愉快
MISSING PERSON
（寻人启事）
Her family must be so worried.
她的家人一定很着急
MISSING PERSON, PLEASE FIND MY MOTHER
（寻找失踪女性 请帮我找妈妈）
Song Ha-young is doing well, right?
宋霞永过得还不错吧？
I've been meaning to get in touch, but I've been too busy.
我想联系他来着 但我太忙了
I thought he'd come with you.
我以为他会和你一起来
Ha-young is…
霞永他…
Did he not want to come because of me?
他是因为我才不想来吗？
-You know how he is, right? -I sure do.
-你也知道他这个人的 对吧？ -当然了
He doesn't hold grudges.
他不是那种心胸狭隘的人
He probably doesn't care what I'm up to.
他可能都不在乎我在忙什么
If you're curious, you could reach out to him first.
你要是好奇 可以主动联系他
Right. I'm sure I'll see him soon anyway.
是啊 我相信反正很快就能见到他
Time will fly by.
时间过得很快
And you may never get a chance.
你可能不会有机会了
Sorry?
什么？
Let's head over to Daejong Lake.
我们去大钟湖吧
Nam Ki-Tae, the suspect in the Southwest Serial Murder Case,
首尔西南部连环杀人案嫌疑人南基泰
showed no remorse for his actions during his first trial last month.
在上个月的第一次审讯中 没有表达丝毫的悔过
His attitude enraged the bereaved families and…
他的态度让死者家属震怒
Why would I feel remorse?
我为什么要抱歉？
I'm not sorry at all. I don't even feel guilty.
我一点都不感到抱歉 也没有负罪感
I'm so sorry, Hwa-yeon.
我对不起你 花妍
I'm sorry, Hwa-yeon.
对不起 花妍
At that intersection up ahead,
受害者家和大钟湖
the road splits up into the victim's home and Daejong Lake.
在那前面十字路口两边
If you turn left and find Daejong Lake.
左转的话 她能到大钟湖
If she wanted to go home, she should've taken a right.
如果她想回家 得往右转
The location of the phone the missing person pinged
失踪者手机定位
right there on the left
显示在左边
and turned off as she went for the lake.
她去湖边的时候手机关机了
Let's say she was abducted.
我们假设她被绑架了
If she was forced to get in his car, he would've taken her phone first.
如果他被强行带上车 罪犯肯定会先抢走她的手机
But the phone of an abducted woman was
但被绑架女子的手机
turned on until she got here.
是到达后才关机的
The last person she talked to was her daughter.
她最后对话的人是她的女儿
After she left the karaoke bar, she didn't make any calls.
她离开练歌房后 没有打过电话
Maybe she volunteered to hop in.
她可能是自愿上车的
Not unless she knew him.
除非她认识那个人
She wouldn't get into a random car.
她不会随便上什么车
Did you question her associates?
你询问过她的同事吗？
Yes.
问了
DAEJONG LAKE
（大钟湖）
GUKIL HOSPITAL
（国一医院）
They came and visited you twice
你在重症监护室的时候
even when you were in the ICU.
他们来看过你两次
You didn't know?
你不知道吗？
A few more visited you other than them.
除了他们 还有几个人来看过你
You weren't aware?
你也不知道吗？
Not just Chief Young-soo?
不只是荣秀股长吗？
Chief Young-soo stops by very often.
荣秀股长经常来看你
Some younger people came too.
年轻的同事们也来过
A woman and a man.
一名女同事和一名男同事
I see.
这样啊
And there were other people from the Seoul Agency,
首尔厅的其他人也来过
someone on the older side.
年纪大的人也来过
Then other people
还有自称是你的首尔厅同事们
who said they're your colleagues lined up to visit you,
你转移到这里躺着的时候
even after you were moved here and bedbound.
他们也来探望你了
Even as you were in bed,
虽然你躺在病床上
all of your colleagues flooded in and visited you,
你的同事们和上司们蜂拥来探望你
so I was really glad.
我真的很欣慰
You didn't know if your son was going to wake up,
你都不知道你儿子能不能醒过来
but you were glad?
你还很欣慰？
Why wouldn't I know that?
我怎么会不知道呢？
I knew you would wake up.
我知道你会醒过来的
How? Even the doctor didn't.
怎么会？医生都没把握
I'm your mom.
我是你妈妈
GUKIL HOSPITAL
（国一医院）
Ha-young is asleep, right?
霞永睡着了吧？
Yes, he fell asleep half an hour ago.
是的 他半小时前睡着了
I see. How was he today?
好的 他今天怎么样？
His rehab is going well,
他的康复治疗做得很好
and he's recovering quickly too.
他恢复得也快
Right, Captain Yoon and Detective Nam stopped by this afternoon.
对了 白天尹组长和南刑警来过
Goodness, he must've felt awkward.
哎呀 他肯定觉得难为情
Only on the outside. He's not like that on the inside.
表面看上去那样 他内心不是那样的
It's not like I've known him only for a couple of days.
我又不是刚认识他没几天
I can tell by his face.
我看他的表情就知道了
Chief Young-soo, you should see Ha-young before you leave.
荣秀股长 你去看看霞永再走吧
I still can't muster up the courage.
我还是鼓不起勇气
Goodness.
哎呀
MANYEON-DONG, GUNPO, GYEONGGI PROVINCE
（京畿道军浦市万延洞）
Excuse me, may I ask you a question?
打扰了 我可以问你一个问题吗？
Oh, I'm not dangerous.
我不是坏人
I wanted to ask you for directions.
我想跟你问一下路
Sure.
好
I'm trying to go to Taepyeong Park. Which way do I need to go?
我想去太平公园 要往哪边走？
It's probably closed right now.
现在应该关门了
Oh, I'm not trying to go there.
我不是要到那儿去
I'm going in that direction.
我只是问一下方向
I see.
这样啊
You can go down this way for about 900 meters.
你可以沿着这条路走大约900米
When you see a big barbecue place on the right, take a right.
等你看到右手边有一家很大的烤肉店 往右转
Turn right at the barbecue place.
在烤肉店右转就可以了
-Yes. And then… -One second.
-是的 然后再… -等一下
I have a bad memory,
我记忆力不太好
so let me write it down.
我先记下来
Hold on.
稍等
I don't have paper or a pen.
我没有纸和笔
It's not that confusing.
没那么复杂的
Turn right at the barbecue place, then the second--
在烤肉店右转然后…
Where are you headed?
你去哪？
Me?
我吗？
If you don't mind, I can give you a ride.
如果你不介意的话 我送你一程吧
The bus will be here soon. It's all right.
公车马上就到了 没关系
I'm driving down anyway.
反正我也往那边去
If you're going in the same direction, I'll give you a ride.
如果你也往那去 我捎你一段吧
No, I'm fine.
不用了
I'm not dangerous, you know.
我不是坏人
That's not why.
不是因为这个
The bus stops near my house,
公交车站就在我家附近
so I'm really fine.
所以真的不用了
Well, the world is now a dangerous place,
好吧 现在世界不太平
so it's not easy to hop in, right?
不方便坐陌生人的车吧
No.
不是的
When will the bus get here?
公交车什么时候来？
Is it the last bus?
是末班车吗？
It's about time it came.
它差不多要到了
Did you miss the last one?
你错过末班车了吗？
Then I can wait with you.
我可以在这陪你等
If you missed the last bus,
如果你错过了
I can give you a ride.
我可以捎你一程
No, I'm really fine.
真的不用了
No, I'll leave after I see you get on the bus.
不 我看你上了公交车 我再走
The last bus left, right?
末班车走了是不是？
It's pretty late,
很晚了
so I have to get going too.
我也得离开了
You really won't get in?
你真的不上车吗？
Will you be okay?
你一个人没关系吗？
I'll go, then.
那我走了
Then can you just tell me the directions once again?
你能再给我指一下方向吗？
Go down this way, then at the barbecue…
沿着这条路走 到了烧烤店…
Why don't you just get in?
你为什么不干脆上车呢？
Why are you so anxious?
你为什么这么不安？
Goodness, it must be cold.
哎呀 一定很冷吧
Hop in.
上车吧
In that case, thank you.
那谢谢你
The bus is here. I'll take that.
公交车来了 我坐公交吧
Take a left at the second intersection.
在第二个十字路口左转
Damn it.
该死
Damn it!
该死！
That bus.
该死的公交车
SEOUL METROPOLITAN POLICE AGENCY
（首尔地方警察厅）
Can you check if there are any similar cases in the Gyeonggi area?
你能查一下京畿道地区 有没有类似的案例吗？
Yes.
好的
The first one wasn't even reported.
第一起没有报案
We can only speculate instead of investigating it.
我们只能推测 不能调查
It's tough to be the judge just with that case.
仅凭那起案件很难判断
Anyway, continue to check if there are any similar cases.
不管怎么说 继续调查 有没有相似的案件
Okay.
好的
-Captain Yoon. -Thank you.
-尹组长 -谢谢
You're here.
你来了
-Chief.
-股长
-Is that for me? -Yes.
-这是给我的吗？ -是的
-Thank you. -Sure.
-谢谢 -不用谢
It feels like I'm on a break drinking coffee away from
走出广域调查队的办公室出来喝咖啡
the Wide-Area Investigation office.
就算时间很短 也有一种休假的感觉
Coffee is about the only thing that can comfort people like us.
只有咖啡能够抚慰 我们这种人的内心了
So…
话说…
is the Analysis Team working on a case?
分析组有什么案子了吗？
Oh, it's Gil-pyo.
哦 是吉票
Superintendent Heo?
许科长吗？
Well, it's a missing case of karaoke bar employees.
练歌房服务员失踪案
He said there was one each in February and April.
他说二月和四月各有一起
He wanted our opinion, so I went to Gyeonggi Agency yesterday.
他寻求我们的看法 所以我昨天去了一趟京畿厅
Did you go alone?
你自己去的吗？
Yes, it's not even that far.
对 反正也不远
But what do you mean the first case
但你说的第一桩案子
was not reported?
没有报警是什么意思？
I overheard you on the phone.
你刚才打电话的时候 我听到了
While they investigated the missing case from April,
调查四月的失踪案时
they found an unreported missing case,
他们发现了未报警的失踪事件
because she lived alone without any family.
因为她是独居女性 没有家人
I see.
原来如此
Right, so what brings you here?
你来这是为了什么事吗？
Detective Nam and I went to visit Inspector Song yesterday.
我昨天和南刑警去探望了宋警卫
I heard.
我听说了
He seemed very exhausted.
他看起来非常疲惫
I think…
我觉得…
he needs some time to himself.
他需要些时间自己静一静
RESIGNATION LETTER
（辞职信）
I don't want to go back.
我不想回去了
I see.
我明白
Don't think about anything else,
别想其他的事了
and just focus on your health while you stay in the hospital.
你在医院的这段时间就专心养病吧
I'm spending
自从我住院
a lot more time with my mother
我大多数时间
since I was hospitalized.
都是和我妈妈度过的
We're having meals together.
我们一起吃饭
And we're talking a lot more.
我们聊天也比以前多得多
I can't even remember the last time I had a normal day like this.
我甚至想不起来 上一次这么平凡的日子是什么时候
I realized that having a normal life like this was the joy of life.
我意识到这些平凡的日常 就是人生的幸福
I've been dealing with only evil, intelligent criminals.
我一直在和邪恶的高智商罪犯周旋
I guess I was fed up with them.
我想我已经受够他们了
-Captain Kook. -Yes.
-尹组长 -你说
Do you think I was only trying to put myself
你说我只是站在他们的角度考虑问题
in their shoes?
是真的吗？
To be honest, what scared me the most
坦白的说 其实我最怕的是…
was the anxiety
我的内心可能
that there might be a different side of me I was not aware of.
存在着我不知道的另一个自己 这让我感到不安
I was scared
我害怕
that even I might turn into them.
我也会成为那种人
For now,
现在
don't let these thoughts get to you. Okay?
不要让这种想法影响你 明白吗？
Just look after yourself and rest.
你只管养好身体 好好休息
I'll get going.
我先走了
And I will hold on to this for now.
这个我就先保管了
Captain Kook.
组长
I don't want to go back.
我不想再回去了
-Chief Kook. -Yes.
-国股长 -你说
I'm here to talk about that.
我来是想谈谈这件事
It's fine. Woo-ju knows everything.
没关系 宇宙什么都知道
Okay.
好的
You watched the interview. So you know
你看过审讯 所以你知道
that they're beyond our imagination.
那些人超乎了你的想象
Those monsters dump out
那帮禽兽会在审讯时
a different kind of trash from the interrogation.
透露不一样的负面信息
And handling this trash
而要面对这些信息
isn't easy.
真的不容易
Right.
是的
And that probably exploded.
而且很可能导致负面情绪爆发
He needs time to empty it out too.
他需要时间去排解
Time to empty it out…
要有排解的时间啊…
You need to take it easy too, Captain Yoon.
尹组长 你也要适当休息
When people keep running without a break,
如果人一直奔跑 不休息
they always trip over and explode.
他们总会摔跟头崩溃的
So…
所以…
what do you plan to do about Inspector Song?
宋警卫的事 你打算怎么办？
I need to wait.
我得等等
After everything he's been through,
经过这一切
I couldn't push him again
我不能再强求他了
because I felt responsible
因为霞永现在的状态
for his current state.
我难辞其咎
PUNGYEON-DONG, ANYANG, GYEONGGI PROVINCE
（京畿道安阳市丰延洞）
KARAOKE
（练歌房）
You're not going to sing?
你不唱歌吗？
No. Let's just talk.
不了 我们聊聊天就好
It's a waste of money.
真是浪费钱
Why don't you sing a song?
你为什么不唱？
I would rather talk to you
比起唱歌
than sing a song.
我宁愿和你说话
Sure. I'll turn off the music.
好吧 我把音乐关了
Shall we go for another round?
我们喝一杯再走？
-What are you doing? -It's fine. Don't be like that.
-你这是干吗？ -没事的 别大惊小怪
Stop it.
住手
Get your hands off me.
把你的手拿开
Stop it!
住手！
Damn it!
该死！
What the hell are you doing?
你这是在干什么？
Hey.
喂
Open up. Unlock the door!
开门 把门打开！
You!
你！
You're ruining my good mood.
你毁了我的好心情
GUKIL HOSPITAL
（国一医院）
SONG HA-YOUNG
（宋霞永）
Excuse me.
不好意思
This is Detective Song Ha-young's room, right?
这是宋霞永警卫的病房吧？
Yes, it is. Why do you ask?
是的 你有什么事吗？
Could you give this to Detective Song?
能把这个转交给宋警卫吗？
Sure.
好的
VOLUNTEER
（义工）
Hey, Ha-young.
霞永
I think she works here as a volunteer.
我觉得她像是这里的义工
But she told me to give this to you and left.
但她让我把这个转交给你就走了
A volunteer?
义工？
Yes. Open it. I'm curious to see what it is.
是啊 打开看看吧 我很好奇是什么
Goodness. What's all this?
天啊 这都是什么？
She must be an excellent cook.
她肯定厨艺了得
Goodness. There's a card too.
哎呀 这里还有封信
-Here. -Right.
-给 -好吧
Goodness. I can't believe this.
哎呀 真是不敢相信
SOS. I can't handle Chief Kook's jokes by myself.
救命 我一个人承受不了 国股长的冷笑话
I hope you get well and come back soon.
希望你早日康复 快点回来
How's the rehab going?
康复治疗怎么样了？
I'm sorry for not visiting you often.
很抱歉我没有经常来探望你
Inspector Song, it's winter now.
宋警卫 冬天到了
It's gotten cold.
天气变冷了
Don't catch a cold, and take care of yourself.
别感冒了 要保重身体啊
RESIGNATION LETTER
（辞职信）
INVESTIGATIVE POINTS
（调查重点）
THE SUSPECT LIVES ALONE
（嫌疑人独自居住）
Think only about the victims…
只考虑被害人…
and the bereaved families.
和他们的家属吧
TOJUNG-DONG, ANYANG, GYEONGGI PROVINCE
（京畿道安阳市土井洞）
Sir, I want to touch that!
叔叔 我想摸一摸它！
Which one? That one?
哪个？这个吗？
That one over there.
那边那个
Come here.
来吧
How pretty.
真漂亮
Is that all?
只摸这个吗？
-No. I want to touch this too! -This one?
-不 我还想摸摸这个！ -这个？
-Right? -Yes.
-对吗？ -是的
EMERGENCY MEDICAL CENTER
（急诊中心）
You seem to be doing much better now.
你现在看上去好多了
Yes, thanks to you.
是的 谢谢您
That's good to hear.
真是太好了
Thank you for the food.
谢谢您送来的餐食
I really enjoyed it.
我真的很喜欢
I should've thanked you sooner.
我应该早点感谢您的
It was long ago,
已经过去很久了
so I didn't think you'd remember me
我还以为你不会记得我呢
since you work on so many cases.
毕竟你要忙那么多案子
I remember everything.
我都记着呢
I remember Ms. Choi Hwa-yeon…
我记得崔花妍女士…
and you too.
还有您
It's just that
只是
I didn't have the courage.
我没有勇气
To face…
再次面对
the victims
受害者们
or their families again.
或是他们的家属
I felt the same way.
我也感同身受
When I think about the scumbag who did that to Hwa-yeon,
想起那个人渣对花妍的所作所为
I still want him to suffer the same.
我还是希望他也尝尝那种滋味
Whenever I'm reminded that he's doing just fine in jail,
只要想到他在监狱中安然地活着
I feel so resentful.
我就非常愤恨
I just want to follow Hwa-yeon and die too.
我真想跟着花妍死了算了
My life has been so miserable.
我活的很艰难
To tell you the truth, I couldn't bring myself
跟您说实话吧 第一次在这里见到您
to say hello to you when I first saw you here
我都没有勇气和您打招呼
because all the horrible memories came rushing back.
因为所有可怕的回忆都卷土重来了
I had nightmares for days.
我做了好多天的噩梦
I thought maybe I should stop
我心想 或许我不应该
volunteering here.
继续在这里当义工了
I'm sorry.
真抱歉
Why are you sorry?
你为什么抱歉？
I should thank you if anything.
我应该感谢你才对
That's why I still had the handkerchief.
所以我一直留着那块手帕
One day, I saw it again
有一天 我又一次看着它
and realized
我突然明白
that I had been able to hold out
我能坚持到现在
thanks to everyone
多亏了所有
who did their best for me and Hwa-yeon.
为了我和花妍拼尽全力的人
And you're one of them.
你也是其中之一
Hold on a moment.
等我一下
-Where are you going? -I'll be right back.
-你去哪里？ -我马上就回来
Just a moment.
一会就好
I ran into you, so I couldn't prepare anything
碰巧遇到您 我没能准备什么东西
Here, take this and eat it.
给 这个拿去吃吧
No, it's okay.
不用了
I bought it just now, so it's still warm.
我刚刚买的 还是温热的呢
Then let's eat it together.
那我们一起吃吧
This is for your recovery
这是为了恭喜你出院
and a small token of my gratitude.
我的一点心意
I read the newspaper articles.
我看了报纸
Just like back then,
就像当时
you only think about the victims and their families.
你只要想着被害人和他们的家属
-Thank you very much. -No problem.
-非常感谢你 -您客气了
Some of the bereaved manage to pluck up the courage to live on,
有些人努力鼓起勇气继续生活
but I'm sure some are still drowning in sorrow.
但我相信也有一些人 依旧沉浸在悲伤中
Please help people like us,
请帮帮我们这样的人吧
so no one else
这样就不会再有人
has to lose their loved ones like that.
失去他们深爱的人了
Joy to the world, the Lord has come
普世欢腾 救主降世
-Inspector Song! -Hey.
-宋警卫！ -你好
-You woke him up. -I'm sorry.
-你把他吵醒了 -对不起
It's okay. I had to get up anyway.
没关系 我反正要起床的
-When did you get here? -Just now.
-你什么时候来的？ -我刚到
Here, this is for you.
给 这是给你的
I picked out the best ones.
我特意挑选了好吃的装进去
Thank you.
谢谢
When will Chief Kook get here?
国股长什么时候来？
I thought he was coming with you.
我以为他会和你一起
He'll be here later.
他会晚点过来
-Have some. -Thank you.
-来点吧 -谢谢
-You too, Reporter Choi.
-你也是 崔记者
You can go home soon, right?
你很快就可以出院回家了吧？
Yes, in two days.
是的 再有两天
After almost six months.
在医院待了快六个月
-How do you feel? -Is this an interview?
-感觉如何？ -这是采访吗？
Come up with better questions.
想些好点的问题吧
Of course, he's excited.
心情肯定好啊
Then what will you do as soon as you get home?
那你回家第一件事要做什么？
I'm not sure.
我不知道
I haven't really thought about it.
我没想过这个问题
Wait, hold on!
等等
Let's go eat something.
我们去吃点东西吧
You want to eat again?
你又想吃东西？
You didn't have dinner?
你没吃晚饭吗？
I did, but I'm hungry again.
吃了 但我又饿了
-It's winter, you know. -She eats a lot.
-冬天容易饿 你懂的 -她很能吃
-It's good to eat a lot. -Oh, Chief Kook.
-能吃是福嘛 -国股长
-You made it. -We waited for you until now.
-你来了 -我们一直在等你
-I see. You're leaving now? -Yes, we are.
-你们要走了吗？ -是啊
You're here.
你来了
Hey.
你好
Get in, guys.
赶紧上来吧
I guess these guys kept you up. You should be in bed now.
我猜这些家伙来了 所以你没睡 你该休息了
You just got here. Are you leaving right away?
你才刚到 这就要走了？
Yes. I mean, no.
对 不是
Actually, I should get going. You need to go to bed.
其实我是该走了 你需要卧床休息
I'm glad to see you looking healthy. I'll be off, then.
很高兴看到你健健康康的 那我先走了
Bye.
再见
-See you in the office. -Okay, good night.
-办公室见 -好 晚安
What did Ha-young say just now?
霞永刚刚说什么了？
"See you in the office."
“办公室见”
What is it?
什么意思？
Excuse me, did you miss the bus just now?
打扰了 你刚刚是不是错过公交车了？
-Pardon? -It's cold.
-什么？ -天气很冷
I can give you a ride.
我可以送你一程
I'm following the bus route anyway,
反正我也走公交车的路线
so I can drop you off along the way.
我可以沿路捎你一段
-This looks so good. -It looks amazing.
-看上去很好吃 -看着不错啊
Eat it with green onions. It's so good.
配着葱吃 太美味了
Inspector Song
宋警卫
looked more high-spirited than ever before.
看望了他那么多次 今天脸色最好
I'm sure he's relieved that he can finally go home.
我猜他终于可以回家了 如释重负
It must've been tough.
这段日子他肯定不好过
Oh, Detective Nam.
南刑警
What are you doing here?
你在这里做什么？
We met at Mapo Police Station and in front of Seoul HQ as well.
我们在麻浦警察局和首尔厅前见过面
You remember me, right?
你还记得我是不是？
I'm Reporter Choi Yoon-ji from Fact Today.
我是《今日真相》的记者崔润智
That's right, Reporter Choi Yoon-ji.
没错 崔润智记者
I'm Nam Il-young, Wide-Area Investigation Squad.
我是南日永 广域调查队的
-Good to see you. -You're always so quick.
-幸会 -你动作一向这么快
-Are you here alone? -I stopped by on my way home.
-你一个人来的吗？ -我回家的路上顺路来的
I'm picking up my late-night snack.
我在买宵夜
-Let's sit down. -Okay.
-我们坐吧 -好
-We were going to order some drinks. -I see.
-我们正准备喝一杯 -这样啊
Excuse me, could we get two more servings?
请再给我们拿两份好吗？
My goodness.
真是的
I don't want to be a third wheel.
我不想当电灯泡
Gosh, no. We're just friends.
哎呀 误会了 我们只是朋友
-Don't even worry about it. -Oh, really?
-你可别担心这个 -真的吗？
You sure know how to enjoy beef intestines.
你很会吃牛肠啊
BUS STOP GEUMCHAN VILLAGE
（公交车站 金村）
Thank you.
谢谢你
Were you out with your friends?
你是和朋友出来的吗？
Yes.
是的
I couldn't just pass by, looking at you freezing.
看你很冷的样子 我不忍心开车过去
Thank you.
谢谢
You can just drop me off along the way.
你顺路送我一程就好
It'll probably start snowing soon.
好像就要下雪了
We should help each other out, you know?
我们应该互相帮助 你觉得呢？
Who knows? Santa Claus may give us a gift.
谁知道呢？圣诞老人可能 会给我们礼物
That's true.
是啊
You deserve a nice Christmas gift for this.
你理应得到一份精美的圣诞礼物
Then how about you give me a gift?
那你给我一个礼物怎么样？
Sorry?
什么？
I want a gift.
我想要一个礼物
Hey.
喂
I had fun thanks to you.
多亏你 我很愉快
CHIEF PARK DAE-WOONG
（广域搜查队股长 朴大雄）
Hello?
喂？
Okay.
好的
Superintendent Heo.
许科长
Another girl has gone missing in Tojung-dong.
土井洞又有一名女孩失踪了
-Again? -I think it's the same guy.
-又一起？ -我觉得是同一个人干的
Give Young-soo a call too.
给荣秀也说一声
FEMALE COLLEGE STUDENT GOES MISSING IN GYEONGGI PROVINCE BEFORE CHRISTMAS
（女大学生圣诞节前在京畿道失踪）
-Chief. -Yes?
-股长 -什么？
We received a missing person's report from Tojung-dong, right?
我们收到过一起土井洞 人口失踪的报案对吗？
Yes. Why do you ask?
是 为什么问这个？
Yes, Chief Park?
朴股长？
Okay. I got it. I'm going to Gyeonggi Agency.
我知道了 我这就去京畿厅
Okay, I'll see you later.
好的 晚点见
Yes, I'll head over right now.
好 我现在就去
-Here's your receipt. -Oh, yes.
-你的收据 -好的
Thank you.
谢谢
I'll get a taxi for you. Go home first.
我给你叫出租车 你先回家
Don't do that, I can take the bus.
不用了 我可以坐公交车
Taxis are more comfortable.
出租车更舒适一点
All right, then. Thank you.
那好吧 谢谢
Take it easy, okay?
你当心一点 好吗？
Yes, don't worry.
好 放心吧
I'm so glad you're getting discharged.
真高兴看到你出院了
I won't scare you like that again. I'm sorry.
我不会再这样吓你了 对不起
-Let me carry that. -It's fine.
-我来拿吧 -没事
-I got it. -You're so stubborn.
-我来吧 -你真固执
-I told you to take it easy. -Let's go.
-我说了要当心一点 -我们走吧
SEOUL METROPOLITAN POLICE AGENCY
（首尔地方警察厅）
Inspector.
宋警卫
-Are you feeling better? -Yes, I'm fine.
-你感觉好些了吗？ -是的 我很好
Why did you come here instead of heading home?
你怎么不回家来这里了？
I'm good to work now.
我现在可以工作了
Where's Chief Kook?
国股长人呢？
He went to the Gyeonggi Agency.
他去京畿厅了
The Gyeonggi Police Agency?
京畿厅？
Why did he go there?
他为什么要去哪里？
TRUSTWORTHY POLICE SAFE AND STRONG COUNTRY
（值得信赖的警察 安全强大的国家）
There was a bus stop in front of the karaoke bar, right?
练歌房前面有个公交车站 对吧？
-Yes, there was. -Okay.
-是的 -好
The missing person's job group is completely different though.
失踪者的工作群体完全不同
But the area is all very similar.
但是现场非常相似
Hey, how did you know I was here?
你怎么知道我在这里？
Are you feeling better?
你身体好些了吗？
Yes.
是的
-It's been a while. -Have you been well?
-好久不见 -你最近还好吗？
Woo-ju briefed me on the case when I got to the office.
我去办公室的时候 宇宙给我简述了案情
Can you explain the case to me in detail?
你能给我详细介绍一下案件吗？
All right. As it was reported here,
好的 如报告所述
a woman went missing from a karaoke bar in April.
4月份有一个女性从练歌房失踪了
But back in February,
但是2月时
another employee from a karaoke bar
另一家练歌房的另一名员工
went missing but it wasn't reported.
也失踪了 但是没有报案
Then two days ago, on the 23rd,
2天前 也就是23号那天
a female university student went missing from the same bus stop.
一名女大学生也在 同一个公交车站失踪了
I think it's the same perp for all three cases.
我觉得这三起都是一个人干的
When we visited the crime scene for the case in April,
我们4月去了案发现场调查
there was a bus stop there too.
那里也有个公交车站
What about the unreported case?
那没有报案的那一例呢？
There was a bus stop there too.
也有一个公交车站
All three cases happened in a desolate area.
三起案件都发生在偏远的地方
He's looking at the location.
他有意选择了那里
You figured that out already?
这么快就想到了？
No witnesses, right?
没有目击者对吧？
That's right.
是的
So if we take Chief Kook's guess and assume that all three
按照国股长的推测 假设这三起案件的绑架地点
were abducted from a bus stop…
都是公交车站…
That means they were waiting for the bus.
那意味着受害人是在等公交车
What time did this happen?
案发时间是什么时候？
All of their phones went radio silent around 1 a.m. in the morning.
她们手机关机都是在凌晨一点左右
They were waiting for the last bus.
她们在等末班车
He might have forced them into the car.
他可能是逼迫她们上车的
Don't you need at least two people to force an adult into your car?
抓成年人上车至少要两个人吧？
They were offered a free ride.
有人提出要免费送她们
-What? -A free ride, you say.
-什么？ -你是说免费搭车
If there are two culprits, there's no good reason
如果有两名罪犯 那就没理由
to abduct women at a bus stop.
在公交车站绑架妇女了
They can just target a woman walking alone and abduct her by force.
他们可以把落单的妇女强行拉上车
I think there's a high chance that it's the same culprit.
我觉得极有可能是同一人所为
-Chief Park. -Yes?
-朴股长 -什么事？
Let's form an investigation team.
我们组成调查组吧
GYEONGGI INVESTIGATION HEADQUARTERS OF SERIAL MISSING WOMEN CASE
（京畿道妇女连环失踪案调查总部）
JANUARY 2007
（2007年1月）
Let us in on the investigation too.
让我们也加入调查吧
We have experience working with the Analysis Team.
我们有和分析组合作的经验
I'm sure we'll come in handy.
我们能帮上忙的
All right, fine.
好吧
I'll ask the Gyeonggi Agency for permission to cooperate.
我会给京畿厅发协助公文
-Thank you, sir. -All right.
-谢谢 -好的
You'll be working at the Gyeonggi Agency for a while, right?
你最近要去京畿厅上班了 是吗？
Yes, probably.
应该是吧
Hold on.
等等
Hey, what should I do with this?
这个我该怎么处理？
Should I rip it up?
我应该把它撕了吗？
RESIGNATION LETTER
（辞职信）
-Come on. -Should I?
-等等 -撕不撕？
You're so twisted.
你真的奇奇怪怪的
Woo-ju. Rip that up into pieces once we leave.
宇宙 我们走后把它给撕了
I'll do as you command.
悉听尊便
-I'm counting on you, Woo-ju. -Sure thing.
-宇宙 我可指望你了 -放心吧
"Woo-ju," please?
那就交“宇”你了？
GYEONGGI PROVINCIAL POLICE AGENCY
（京畿地方警察厅）
-Let's get started then. -Yes, sir.
-我们开始吧 -好的
MISSING WOMEN CASES IN GYEONGGI
（京畿道妇女连环失踪案）
There were no security cameras at the scene.
现场没有监控
Most of those areas don't have any.
这些地区大都没有监控
They're building new apartment complexes there.
他们正在那里建造新的公寓楼
The district office didn't even look for installation spots.
区政府甚至还没找监控安装点
The culprit knows the area is pretty desolate
罪犯知道这地方人迹罕至
with no security cameras.
没有监控
I think we should install security cameras not just in this area,
我觉得我们应该安装监控 不仅是这片区域
but also at every bus stop with no security cameras in Gyeonggi.
还有京畿道每一个 没有监控的公交车站
-Every single one? -Yes, switch out the old ones too.
-每一个吗？ -是的 把旧的也给换了
You can barely make out license plates with the older models.
旧的监控连车牌号都拍不清
You think it's that simple?
你觉得这是说说就能完成的事吗？
The Ministry of Finance has to…
财政部得…
Fine. I'll talk to them.
好 我去跟他们提
Then I'll check for areas with no security cameras.
那我去确认没有监控的地点
-All right. -Thanks, I appreciate it.
-好的 -谢谢 辛苦了
A SAFE COUNTRY WITH HAPPY CITIZENS A COUNTRY OF SECURITY POWER
（公民幸福 国家安全稳定）
Have you been well?
你最近还好吗？
Yes, thanks to you.
挺好的 托你的福
Thanks to me?
托我的福？
You played a part in my joining the Analysis Team.
你允许我加入了分析组
I see you can make jokes now.
看来你现在会开玩笑了
The rumors about Chief Kook whipping you into shape was true.
看来国股长真的让你学会了为人处世
Yes, he sure did.
这是事实
I was appointed to a new station so suddenly,
那时候命令突然下来
so I couldn't reach out.
所以我没能和你联络
Anyone would've done the same thing.
任何人都会这么做的
It's all in the past now.
现在都过去了
I'm just glad we met again.
我很高兴我们又见面了
Let's do our best.
我们尽力干吧
Did you hear the rumors about you whipping me into shape?
你听到你教会我为人处世的传闻了？
What kind of absolute nonsense is that?
哪儿来的风言风语？
Who whipped who into what?
谁教谁啊？
People just love to gossip.
大家就是喜欢这些传闻
What's wrong with it?
这有什么错？
Don't let rumors bother you.
别让流言影响你
It's true though.
不过这倒是真的
The buses run in 40 to 50-minute intervals.
车辆运行间隔是40分钟到50分钟
That's quite a wait.
挺久的
Right. There aren't many taxis either.
是啊 那里也没什么出租车
Even more so at night.
晚上更是如此了
He probably had that in mind.
他很可能就是盯上了这一点
The security camera installation is finalized, right?
安装监控这事已经敲定了吧？
Yes. They'll install more in the areas of disappearance
是的 他们会在失踪地
and all nearby locations.
和周边地区安装更多的监控
SINBON 2-DONG OFFICE
（新本二洞办事处）
I hope the cameras help.
希望监控能有用
I'm sure he'll be more cautious with the lack of blind spots.
我相信没有监控死角 他会更谨慎的
It's been over nine months now.
已经九个多月了
I hope they are alive.
希望失踪者们还活着
At least none of the missing women were found dead.
至少还没有发现失踪女性的尸体
Yes, you're right.
你说的对
We should be hopeful.
我们应该心存希望
Let's go over there.
我们去那儿看看吧
He's the statistical analyst of the Analysis Team.
他是分析组的数据分析师
His name is Jung Woo-ju. He's a smart guy.
他叫郑宇宙 是个聪明的小伙
My name is Yoon Tae-gu.
我叫尹泰九
I'll leave.
我先走了
Did you have customers who offered to give people a ride?
你有没有客人提出要开车送你？
BUS STOP
（公交车站）
It's cold. Hop in.
挺冷的 上车吧
-I'll take you to the main street. -Right.
-我载你去主干道 -好的
SUSPECT ANALYSIS
（嫌疑人分析）
PROFILING REPORT
（京畿道女性连环失踪案剖析报告）
GYEONGGI INVESTIGATION HEADQUARTERS OF SERIAL MISSING WOMEN CASE
（京畿道女性连环失踪案调查总部）
All three cases broke out when the wind chill factor was low.
三件案子都发生在温度很低的天气
It was a secluded area, so buses didn't come often.
那地方很偏僻 所以公交车不多
I stood alone at the bus stop,
我独自站在公交车站
but a truck came by and offered me a ride out into the main street.
一辆卡车经过 提出送我去主干道
You won't find a bus here even if you waited.
就算你在那儿等也不会有公交车的
The culprit takes advantage of the victim's situation and psychology.
罪犯利用了受害人的处境和心理
The buses don't run often,
公交车不多
so it's common for people to give rides
所以附近的人们
in that neighborhood.
搭车是常事
On a cold day, it must've been easier.
天气寒冷 骗人上车就更容易了
So the culprit used the kind face as a mask to lure them?
所以罪犯假装好意 诱骗了她们？
Yes.
是的
Even so, how can they gladly hop into a stranger's car?
即便如此 她们怎么可以 高高兴兴地上了陌生人的车呢？
They didn't hop in gladly.
她们并没有高高兴兴地上车
The culprit must've convinced them to hop in.
罪犯肯定花了心思劝她们上车
Then the culprit must drive a luxurious sedan that seems familiar.
罪犯肯定是开着一辆 大众熟知的豪华轿车
Or have something in his car that drives away people's suspicion.
或者他的车里有什么可以打消疑虑
A family photo? Or stuffed animals?
一张全家福？或是毛绒玩具？
-A baby? -Let's say a baby is in the car.
-一个婴儿？ -假设车里有个婴儿
Then people rarely ask anybody else to join them.
一般不会让人搭车的
The first thing the victim looks at is the driver.
受害者首先看的是司机
So I think the suspect may look amicable,
所以我猜嫌疑人看上去和善可亲
someone who doesn't draw people's suspicion.
是不会引起人们疑心的人
I'm sure the culprit isn't intimidating.
我相信罪犯看着并不吓人
Must be likable.
肯定很和善
You're right.
你说的对
Hello? Chief Kook.
喂？国股长
I'll send you a fax. Please take a look at it.
我给你发个传真 请你过目
Yes, a cold case for a missing person.
对 一起失踪悬案
Yes, in Gunpo.
对 在军浦
GUNPO
（军浦）
Yes, I'll check.
好 我看看
One second.
请稍等
Woo-ju just sent over a missing person case.
宇宙刚发来了一个失踪案
The victim is Heo Geum-young, 51 years old, who went missing in Gunpo.
受害者是在军浦失踪的51岁的许金英
And is it similar?
是不是很相似？
She went missing
她是在一个人迹罕至的
at a bus stop in a secluded area.
公交车站失踪的
Her phone battery got separated around that area.
她的手机电池被拆下丢在了附近
Seems possible.
有这个可能
-He sent us a fax. -I'll pick it up.
-他发给我们传真了 -我去拿
No, I got it.
我来吧
I'm going to the restroom.
我正要去洗手间
-She was 51 years old? -Yes.
-她当时51岁？ -是的
Hey.
喂
We just heard about the cold case in Gunpo--
我们刚听说军浦的悬案
Yes. One second.
是 稍等
Hey, don't hang up.
喂 别挂电话
It's a word on a missing case.
这是一个关于失踪案件的消息
No, not the Gunpo cold case. Not that one. Something else.
不 不是军浦的悬案 是另一起
Suwon Seobu Police Station.
水原西武警察局
An office worker, in her thirties.
一名三十多岁的办公室女职员
That neighborhood recently became filled with industrial parks.
那地方附近新建了很多工厂
The missing person worked in Haeyong Industrial Park.
失踪者在海英工业区上班
She usually commuted by bus at the bus stop
她通常在公司前面的公交车站
in front of her workplace.
乘公交车通勤
That area only has industrial parks around,
那里只有工厂
so everything is pitch dark at night.
所以一到晚上 周围就很黑
Her phone battery was pulled out at 7 a.m. the next morning.
第二天早上七点她的手机电池被拆下
MISSING PERSON
（失踪人员）
A HILL IN ANSAN, GYEONGGI PROVINCE
（京畿道安山市某山）
Hello, Chief Park?
朴股长
We found Yoon Jin-sil's body.
我们找到了尹真实的尸体
The karaoke bar employee who went missing in January.
一月份失踪的那个练歌房员工
Did you see the news?
你看到新闻了吗？
She went missing, then was found buried in secret.
她失踪了 而后被发现被人秘密掩埋
I should check on my wife.
我应该打电话给我老婆
That's horrendous.
太吓人了
MISSING KARAOKE BAR EMPLOYEE IN HER THIRTIES, FOUND DEAD IN ANSAN
（练歌房失踪员工 尸体现于安山）
Get up here!
快找！
Go up!
仔细找！
Something might come out, so keep digging up there!
可能会有线索 继续找线索
Yes!
是！
FOUND NAKED WITH STOCKINGS TIED AROUND THE NECK
（发现时赤身裸体 下身绑着丝袜）
GYEONGGI PROVINCIAL POLICE AGENCY
（京畿地方警察厅）
Ansan is pretty far from the last phone signal
安山距离手机信号消失的地点
and where she went missing.
以及她的失踪地很远
You're right.
你说得对
Why didn't he go near Anyang?
他问什么要来安阳附近？
I'm not sure why he went all the way to Ansan to bury her.
我不清楚他为什么大老远来安山埋尸
The farther one travels, the riskier it becomes.
他跑得越远 风险就越高
He probably didn't make a move by day.
他可能白天没有行动
He went around at night when it was difficult
他在晚上开车
to spot his car on camera.
监控不容易识别他的车
He either lived in Gyeonggi for a long time,
他不是在京畿道住了很久
or he must know the area well.
就是很了解这个地方
Gimpo, Anyang, Suwon, and Ansan.
金浦 安阳 水原还有安山
He usually found the most secluded areas.
他通常会找最偏僻的地方
Lots of places don't show up on GPS in that area.
很多地点在导航里都不显示
You're right, on top of that, he buried her
你说的没错 他甚至在离道路
in a hill 80m away from the road.
有80米远的山里埋了她
If it hadn't been for that elderly man
要不是每天进出深山的
who goes there every day,
那位老年人
it would've been impossible for an ordinary person to spot.
普通人不可能发现那个地方
Then let's find the cars
我们先从监控
that we can distinguish
识别到的车辆
from the security footage.
开始排查吧
We have no choice
我们没有其他办法了
but to narrow down our suspects to ex-convicts living in Gyeonggi.
只能将嫌疑人范围缩小到 住在京畿道的前科犯
There must be a reason why he chose this spot.
他选那个地方一定有原因
Once we find some suspects, we'll also find the reason.
我们找到嫌疑人 也就会找到原因
Detective Nam. Put together a list of ex-convicts.
南刑警 整理一份前科犯的名单
Yes, sir.
是
AN YU-YEON
（安有妍）
You're sound asleep.
你睡得真香
INSERT CARD
（插入银行卡）
PLEASE ENTER YOUR PIN
（请输入密码）
Please take your cash.
请取走您的现金
Your transaction has been completed.
您的交易已完成
Thank you for using Hanyoung Bank.
感谢使用韩英银行
CCTV FOOTAGE EVIDENCE
（监控录像证据）
Was this the person you saw?
你看到的是这个人吗？
Yes, his hair and outfit were odd, so I remember him.
是的 他的发型和服装很古怪 所以我记得他
-He had this bushy bang. -I see.
-他留着厚重的刘海 -好的
And he was wearing a dress shirt with sweatsuit pants.
而且他穿着正装衬衫和运动裤
-Was this the jacket too? -Yes.
-外套是这件吗？ -是的
He looked at me after he withdrew the money,
他取完钱后看了我一眼
so I stared back.
所以我也回看了他
Did you see where he went?
你看到他往哪里走了吗？
I wouldn't know.
我不知道
I saw him catching a taxi.
我看他上了辆出租车
A taxi?
出租车？
A female university student in Gunpo has been missing for 18 days,
军浦的女大学生已经失踪18天
so the police began an open search.
警方展开公开调查
The police obtained footage of a man in his twenties to thirties
警方获得的录像显示 一名二十多岁至三十多岁的男子
withdrawing 700,000 won with this woman's debit card at a bank.
在一家银行用这名女性的借记卡 取走了70万韩元
He's now openly wanted as the key suspect.
他现在作为主要嫌疑人被公开通缉
Yes, all right.
好吧
I checked with the taxi company,
我和出租车公司核实了
and they haven't found the driver yet.
他们还没有找到那名司机
If he took a taxi, he probably lives near the bank.
如果他坐了出租车 他可能就住在银行附近
The bank is close to where she went missing.
银行离她的失踪地也很近
It won't be easy, but let's check every security camera
虽然这很麻烦 我们要检查从失踪点
on the streets from the missing point to the bank.
到银行的街道上的每一个监控记录
We'll check every footage within six kilometers of the bank.
我们要检查银行 方圆六千米内的每一个监控
Everything?
每一个吗？
There are at least over 300 cameras out there.
那里至少有三百个监控摄像头
Yes, we'll check everything.
是的 每一个我们都要看
Please cooperate.
请配合工作
-Okay.
-好的
Right here.
就是这里
What were you doing then?
你当时在做什么？
I was at home.
我当时在家
Darn it.
该死
Let's keep trying.
我们继续努力吧
Gyeonggi 89.
京畿道89号
-Thank you. -You're welcome.
-谢谢 -不客气
Hold on.
等等
Could you rewind the footage just now?
你能把刚才那个画面后退一点吗？
Yes. That one. Please zoom in.
对 就是这个 放大一点
-Chief Kook. Come over here. -Yes?
-国股长 快来看 -什么？
STAY TUNED FOR THE EPILOGUE
（稍后播出后记）
Gosh.
天啊
I've been working in the force for about 30 years.
我当警察都快30年了
And in my opinion,
依我看
you're the best cop in Korea.
你是全韩国最优秀的警察
That was out of the blue.
怎么没来由地这么说
I've never seen you second guess yourself.
我从来没有见你怀疑过自己
You only focus on your job. You don't let the job get to you.
你只专注于工作 你不会被工作牵着鼻子走
So for the past 20 years, I have been watching you
所以过去的20年里 我一直在看你
doing so well without much trouble.
做得这么好 没有什么麻烦
And I realized that people like you were born to be police officers.
我明白了 你这样的人 天生就是当警察的料
And I was proud to have a competent junior like you.
我很骄傲有你这样的后辈
But the guy you scouted, Song Ha-young,
不过你带来的那小子 宋霞永
is just like you.
他和你一模一样
He reminds me of you in every sense.
他方方面面都让我想到了你
How does he remind you of me?
他怎么会让你想到我呢？
Ha-young is young, handsome,
霞永年轻帅气
and looks great with a perm.
一头卷发很好看
You two can't see it.
你们俩没发现
But in other people's eyes,
但是在其他人眼里
Kook Young-soo and Song Ha-young…
国荣秀和宋霞永
are the same.
如出一辙
So that got me worried all of a sudden.
所以这不由得让我担心
Worried about whom?
担心谁？
Isn't it obvious? It's you.
这不是明摆着的吗？担心你啊
Why? I'm a grown man.
为什么？我已经是成年人了
It's easy to come back after running away once.
逃跑一次后 很容易回来
But…
但是…
two people who never thought about running away
从没想过逃离的两个人
ended up working together.
最后却一起工作
So I was worried that…
所以我很担心
both of you might give up if one of you crumbled down.
如果你们中的一个撑不住 另一个也会放弃
You do have a point.
你说的有道理
That's how I feel right now.
我现在就是这种感受
Just like you said, I've been wrong for the last 20 years.
正如你所说 过去的20年我都错付了
It doesn't feel like I've been focusing on my job.
感觉我没有把精力放在工作上
Because I was too busy with my job,
可能因为我过度忙于工作
perhaps I failed to take care of those around me.
或许我对身边的人疏于照顾
And I wonder if I've been doing it wrong the whole time.
我想知道我是不是一直都错了
Young-soo.
荣秀
Cops are human too.
警察也是人
Get in. I had fun today.
上车吧 今天我很尽兴
-Let's grab one more drink. -We've had enough.
-我们再喝一杯吧 -我们喝的够多了
-Sir, please drive him home safely. -Sure.
-请把他安全送回家 -没问题
Apartment Complex Seven in Mok-dong.
木洞七号公寓楼
-You can go. -One more drink.
-你可以走了 -再喝一杯吧
-Bye. -Wait.
-再见 -等等
One more!
再来一杯！
Thanks, Gil-pyo!
谢了 吉票！
Woo Ho-sung?
禹浩成？
Are you suspecting me? Do you have evidence?
你怀疑我？你有证据吗？
We can't let this guy buy time. He'll destroy all the evidence.
我们不能让这家伙争取到时间 他会毁了所有证据
This bastard is unbelievable.
这个混蛋真是不可理喻
What if I'm not the culprit?
如果我不是罪犯呢？
I'm sure he was psychologically pressured.
他曾经一定遭受过精神压迫
-Who's calling? -This is Woo Ho-sung.
-是谁？ -我是禹浩成